A Guide to the Ethel Holsinger Papers, 1792-1881
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Ethel Holsinger Papers, 1792-1881
The Library of Virginia
21770
7 leaves and 13 pages
Ethel Holsinger
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Ethel Holsinger of Charlottesville, Virginia, 4 September 1940.
Biographical Information
Ethel Holsinger was born 12 March 1897 in Charlottesville, Virginia to Rufus W. Holsinger (1866-1930) and Sadie L. Anderson Holsinger. A portrait painter and an antiques dealer, Holsinger died 4 January 1981 in Charlottesville, and was buried at Monticello Memory Gardens.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1792-1872, collected by Ethel Holsinger (1897-1981) of Charlottesville, Virginia, consisting of an appointment by Lieutenant Governor James Wood (1741-1813) of justices of the peace for Franklin County, Virginia; a processioners' return for Franklin County; deed for property in Franklin County, and in Augusta County and Staunton, Virginia; a plat for land in Louisa County, Virginia; voucher and return for hogs supplied to the Confederate army; a receipt for corn supplied to the Confederate army; a letter, including a receipt, discussing the difficulties facing farmers during the Civil War; a railroad pass issued to a Confederate officer allowing him and his servant to travel to Richmond, Virginia; and a Democratic ticket for local elections in Albemarle County, Virginia, in 1881.
Contents List
- Appointment, 25 August 1792, by lieutenant Governor James Wood (1741-1813) of Joshua Rentfroe, Josiah Woods, and Philemon Southerland (d. 1811) as justices of the peace for Franklin County, Virginia.
- Processioners' return, March 1804, made by James Wray and James Wright, both of Franklin County.
- Deed, 30 August 1809, from Walter Bernard (1758-1841), of Franklin County, granting Edmund Tate (d. 1829), also of Franklin County, the right to sell certain lands.
- Plat, 3 April 1847, for 100 acres of land made by William L. Clark for Benjamin Hudson, both of Louisa County, Virginia.
- Deed, dated 1 January 1863 and recorded 26 January 1863, for property in Staunton from Edwin M. Taylor (1815-1870) and Jane Taylor (b. 1819) to Nicholas K. Trout (ca. 1818-1876), all of Augusta County, Virginia.
- Deed for release of property in trust, dated 30 January 1863 and recorded 17 February 1863, from Trout to Edwin Taylor.
- Railroad pass, 25 March 1863, from Provost Marshall Theodore A. Granger (b. ca. 1829) of North Carolina to Major Randolph and his servant allowing them to travel from Goldsboro, North Carolina, to Richmond, Virginia (this is attached to notes about French history and language).
- Return, 3 May 1864, from George W. Clark (ca. 1801-1882) of Madison County, Virginia, to the Confederate States of America supplying data on the hogs Clark has slaughtered.
- Voucher, 7 January 1865, from Captain C. B. Duncan to Clark for hogs received for the Confederate army.
- Deed, dated 1 October 1866 and recorded 2 August 1872, for 130 acres in Augusta County from Margaret A. Tate (1819-1907), Letitia Margaret Tate (1844-1939), and Rebecca Charlotte Tate (b. 1839) to Dr. John M. Tate (1829-1896), all of Augusta County.
- Democratic ticket, 26 May 1881, for local offices in Albemarle County, Virginia.
- Letter, no date, and with no correspondent's name, discussing the difficulties facing farmers during the Civil War, and includes a receipt, dated 18 March 1864, from Major Norman R. Fitzhugh (1831-1914) to Philip Edge (1812-1888) of Albemarle County and an order from Captain James Marshall Hanger (1833-1912) for Edge's corn.